Drew Holbrook

Summary

I'm a software engineer based in Crested Butte, Colorado. I'm a co-creator of Ekko, an open-source realtime service with in-transit message processing, which was built with a team of fully remote software engineers. I have multiple years of experience with the Ruby and Javascript ecosystems and am comfortable with AWS and Docker.

Professional Experience

2021	nresent	

Co-Creator, Software Engineer

Ekko ☑

- Co-created Ekko, an open-source realtime service with in-transit message processing
- Built the websocket server using Node.js, socket.io, and Redis
- Designed the AWS cloud infrastructure (Application Load Balancer, Elastic Container Service with Fargate deployment, S3, Elasticache, Lambda)
- Containerized server code for deployment (Docker, Elastic Container Registry)
- Built CLI tool that deploys and manages Lambdas with AWS SDK and abstracts away complex infrastructure deployment process using AWS Cloud Development Kit
- Load tested the real-time service using artillery.io to simulate 50,000 concurrent connections publishing 300,000 messages per minute
- Collaborated daily with a team of fully remote engineers
- Co-authored Ekko's case study: ekko-realtime.com

2018 - 2021

Full-Stack Web Developer

Self Employed

- Requestbin: Clone of popular tools to capture and store lists of incoming HTTP requests using Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL
- Shopping Cart: React/Redux front-end, Node.js, Express, MongoDB REST API backend
- Ello: Trello-like app with React/Redux front-end, Node.js, Express, MongoDB REST API backend
- Todo List: a todo tracker built with Node.js, Express, JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars, HTML and CSS

2015 - 2018

Director of Marketing and Development

Crested Butte Nordic ☑

Revamped marketing plan which helped increase revenue by 25% over three years

2014 - 2015

Director of Events

Crested Butte Nordic ☑

• Managed over 100 volunteers and organized events for more than 1000 participants

Skills

Backend	Frontend	Tooling	Cloud
Node.js, Express, Ruby,	JavaScript (ES6)	Git/GitHub, Docker, Linux	AWS, Digital Ocean,
Go, PostgreSQL, SQL,	React/Redux		Heroku
MongoDB, RESTful APIs	HTML/CSS		

Education

2004 - 2008

B.A. Economics

University of Vermont ☑